[Music]
hello I'm Andreas chat your Tech curious
web designer in this video we will
explore how to deploy a Jango app with
postest database to railway so Railway
is a highly popular web hosting solution
especially in the python Community it
offers a userfriendly dashboard
interface is straightforward to set up
and although not free it offers a
lowbudget hobby plan let me give you
first a quick demo and after that we
jump straight into the code and deploy
our Jango app in easy to follow steps
let's
go so we can see here the homepage of
Railway and we can start a new project
by simply clicking this button here I
can show you how the interface of a
running application looks like so let's
go inside
this is my workspace here at the moment
I have only one project the awesome
project let's check it
out now we're inside a project in a
production environment and I set here up
two Services a web application connected
to a GitHub repository with the name
Railway and a postest
database unique here is that this
interface is like a big canvas we can
move it
around and add more components if you
like let's check out now our web
application we have a panel popup here
we can see a history of our
deployments then under variables we have
our environment
variables
metric and under settings we can for
example create our domain and other
custom
domain all right that was a quick demo
let me give you a quick overview now of
the steps we will take in this
tutorial so first we will make the
database connection and migrate the
tables the second step is to make the
connection to our GitHub
repository third step is to add the
environment variables to our web service
fourth step is to set up the allowed
hosts fifth step is to configure The
csrf Trusted Origins
six step is to create a proc file which
contains the start command and the
runtime. txt file which declares the
python version these two files are not
required on Railway but
recommended seventh step is to deploy
the application and if this is
successful we will as final step test
the website
online I want to mention also some
prerequisites which I will not go
through in this tutorial and these are
how to set up the EnV file and the
environment variables how to set up a
requirements.txt file which has to
include packages like gunicorn this is
our web server which runs the
application in production the dj-
databaseurl package with this package we
can connect to the database using our
URL then the psychop pg2 D binary
package this is a postgressql adapter
for python so they can communicate with
each other
and then the White Noise package which
we need to serve static files in
production additionally to serve images
we need to set up also the static files
configurations and run the collect
static command we also need to have our
code committed to a GitHub repository
ready to be deployed to the web server
these are standard requirements for any
D Jango deployment so if you have not
set them up yet check out my tutorial
videos on how to deploy a Jango app you
can find the link in the description
below okay let's get started first we
create our postgress
database so I click here provision
postgressql this will make Railway
initialize a post database deploying the
database okay our database is set up now
it also chose a name for our project so
fun smash let's rename the project now
so we go to
settings and here's the name and I
rename my project to
awesome okay and
update and the name is updated
nice let's connect now this database to
our Jango
app I click the variables tab to see the
connection information we're using our
URL to connect to our database so we can
choose here the private URL which has a
few more privacy features or just the
standard URL let's go with the standard
one so I'm copying here the value and go
to my
code I'm heading over to the EnV file in
the core
folder and add the URL to my database _
URL
variable okay save this file then I go
to my settings to be WiFi
I go to the database
configuration here it is so we are
connected to this database when the
environment variable is set to
production or the variable postgress
locally is set to true we're using the
DJ database URL package to connect to
the database and we're using the
database URL environment
variable so let's migrate our table now
to this database so I switched to this
variable now to
true that gives me access now to the
remote
database and now I'm ready to
migrate so python manage to
Pi
migrate it is creating now the tables in
the remote postrest
database let's go to railway and check
it
out I go here to the data tab
we can see here the creation in real
time all right the tables are created
now next let's create our super
user so python manage to Pi create super
user for username I choose
admin we can skip the email address
address
password and the super user is created
awesome so the database is set up I
changed my postest locally variable back
to
false save this file and let's go back
to railway now and create our web
application so I close this panel
here I click new
here then I'm connecting now to my
GitHub
repository my repon GitHub is called
Railway okay the connection is
established and first let's deploy this
application at this stage this will fail
because we have not set up all the
required configurations but we will do
that in a second so I click here this
button
deploy it is initializing the build now
okay it is deployed let's click on
it now first let's import the
variables here we import the environment
variables our project needs so I click
here on Raw
editor and copy and paste all my
variables so I go back to my
project to my EnV file copy
everything and paste it in here
then I change the environment to
production I get rid of the developer
variable this is just for the local
environment all right and then update
variables great now our environment
variables are added then I'm going to
the settings
tab here under the networking we create
now our URL so I click here on generate
domain
so this is a random domain Railway
created for us if we are not happy with
it we can also change
it so let's go with awesome Dash
flicker okay this domain is still
available
update here we can also add a custom
domain if we have
one and now we got our URL so if we
click on this link here
we got the URL working but obviously no
response yet because we have not yet
finished the
setup so let's copy the
domain and let's go back to the
code back to the settings topi file and
let's set up now the allowed
hosts so this is what you see when you
first install Jango so it gives you a
empty list but in production this
variable needs a host so we could for
example
write the Asterix which is the symbol of
a wild card so every host is allowed but
this is not very secure so let's list
here all the host now which we allow
access to our app so first I add my
local hosts so Local
Host then also the local IP address so
127.0.0.1
and then I'm adding here the remote
host so this is the domain I just
created okay these are the allow hosts
another variable we need is the csrf
trusted
Origins and here we add the URL of our
website so again I add here my domain
with the HTTP in
front Railway gives me a secure HTTP
connection out of the box so write
https column SL
slash okay this variable is set up now
as well we can save this
file and we could deploy this
application already on Railway this
would work however it is recommended to
add a proc file with a start command and
a runtime. txt file for the python
version as well so let's do that too I
go to the of my project create a new
file the proc
file like that with no file
extension and here we add the process
type which is
web then the web server we're using
we're using
gunicorn and then the application we
will like to run and the application is
in the whiskey file in our aore core
folder so so aore core do
whiskey like that okay save this file
now next the runtime. txt
file again in the root of our
project this file just declares which
python version we are using so I'm
writing
python Dash and in my case it is
3.1.3
okay that's it save this file and now
let's push these updated files to
GitHub I name this commit deploy to
railway then push
origin then back to
railway here I still have to deploy the
environment variables I set up before so
I click this
button
and the new build has been
initialized a few minutes
later okay our app is deployed now we
can see our latest commit is displayed
here and let's check out the website now
so
refresh and voila our website is
online now let's do some testing and
populate the website I add a category
then I sign up with a new user
and post the image from flicker so first
I'm logging into my admin
interface I create a category so I'm
going to my text
table add
Tech lscape
okay then I also add my new domain to
the SES
table so here instead of example.com we
add our
domain and display name
awesome okay and
save then back to the
homepage and our category is added here
great now sign up with a new user so I
log out from
admin create a new
account add a profile
image okay and
submit our profile is created now let's
create a
post I find an image on
flicker
I choose this one a nice picture of a
lake copy the URL and create a
post all right nice we successfully
deployed our app now to
railway if you like this kind of content
subscribe to this channel for more
awesome front end and backend tutorials
and please leave a comment below that
you subscribed that would help me a lot
with a YouTube algorithm thank you I see
you in the next one stay curious my
[Music]
[Applause]
friends